Guide to the Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees: 1915-1985
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees: 1915-1985
5488 B
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees.
669 linear feet.
Correspondence, Rule books, Agreements, etc.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
SUBJECTS
Names:
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees.
Subjects:
Railroads--Employees--Labor unions--United States--Sources.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted. Please contact the Kheel Center Reference Archivist for access information.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
This forms a portion of collection #5488 B. The guide to the entire collection is available here.
Series LVIII is arranged in 60 sub-series by Union file number.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series LVIII. STRIKES
  - Sub-Series 342-0. Strikes
    - 1963 Rules Movement and Stabilization of Employment and Wage Increase Movement., 1965 (Box 515, Folder 6)
      January-November 1965.
    - 1963 Rules Movement and Stabilization of Employment and Wage Increase Movement, 1964 (Box 515, Folder 7)
    - 1963 Rules Movement and Stabilization of Employment and Wage Increase Movement. Certification of Strike Ballots by Property in Alphabetical Order. A-B, 1964 (Box 515, Folder 8)
    - 1963 Rules Movement and Stabilization of Employment and Wage Increase Movement. Certification of Strike Ballots by Property in Alphabetical Order. C, 1964 (Box 515, Folder 9)
    - 1963 Rules Movement and Stabilization of Employment and Wage Increase Movement. Certification of Strike Ballots by Property in Alphabetical Order. D-J, 1964 (Box 515, Folder 10)
    - 1963 Rules Movement and Stabilization of Employment and Wage Increase Movement. Certification of Strike Ballots by Property in Alphabetical Order. K-N, 1964 (Box 515, Folder 11)
    - 1963 Rules Movement and Stabilization of Employment and Wage Increase Movement. Certification of Strike Ballots by Property in Alphabetical Order. O-S, 1964 (Box 515, Folder 12)
    - 1963 Rules Movement and Stabilization of Employment and Wage Increase Movement. Certification of Strike Ballots by Property in Alphabetical Order. T-Z, 1964 (Box 515, Folder 13)
    - General, 1964 (Box 515, Folder 14)
    - General, 1960-1963 (Box 516, Folder 1)
    - Order of Railroad Telegraphers and Chicago and Northwestern Railroad, 1962-1963 (Box 516, Folder 2)
    - Order of Railroad Telegraphers and Chicago and Northwestern Railroad. Clippings, 1962 (Box 516, Folder 3)
      1962 August, 31
    - Marine Employees, Seafarers International Union, Port of New York, 1961 (Box 516, Folder 4)
    - General. Canada, 1961 (Box 516, Folder 5)
    - General. 1961 Wage and Rules Movement (Box 516, Folder 6)
    - Switchmen's Union of North America, 1960 (Box 516, Folder 7)
    - General, 1958-1959 (Box 516, Folder 8)
      November 1958-59.
    - General, 1958 (Box 516, Folder 9)
      May-October 1958.
    - General, 1957-1958 (Box 516, Folder 10)
      September 1957-April 1958.
    - General, 1957 (Box 516, Folder 11)
      January-August 1957.
    - Louisville and Nashville Railway Company; Western Railway of Alabama; Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway Company; Clinchfield Railway Company; Atlanta Joint Terminal Railways; and Augusta Union Station, 1954-1985 (Box 516, Folder 12)
      October 1954-March 1985.
    - Louisville and Nashville Railway Company; Western Railway of Alabama; Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway Company; Clinchfield Railway Company; Atlanta Joint Terminal Railways; and Augusta Union Station, 1955 (Box 516, Folder 13)
      March 1955-April 12, 1955.
    - Louisville and Nashville Railway Company; Western Railway of Alabama; Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway Company; Clinchfield Railway Company; Atlanta Joint Terminal Railways; and Augusta Union Station. Appeal of Shelton, B.D. and Ballentine, J, 1955-1956 (Box 516, Folder 14)
    - Louisville and Nashville Railway Company; Western Railway of Alabama; Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway Company; Clinchfield Railway Company; Atlanta Joint Terminal Railways; and Augusta Union Station. Appeal of Ballentine, J. Transcript, 1955 (Box 516, Folder 15-17)
      1955 August 19
    - Louisville and Nashville Railway Company; Western Railway of Alabama; Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway Company; Clinchfield Railway Company; Atlanta Joint Terminal Railways; and Augusta Union Station. Appeal of Shelton, B.D. Transcript, 1955 (Box 516, Folder 18-20)
    - Louisville and Nashville Railway Company; Western Railway of Alabama; Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway Company; Clinchfield Railway Company; Atlanta Joint Terminal Railways; and Augusta Union Station. Strike Benefit Payrolls, 1955 (Box 516, Folder 21)
    - General, 1956 (Box 516, Folder 22)
      April-December 1956.
    - General, 1955-1956 (Box 517, Folder 1)
      July 1955-March 1956.
    - General, 1954-1955 (Box 517, Folder 2)
      September 1954-June 1955.
    - Louisville and Nashville Railway Company; Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway Company; Atlanta and West Point Railway Company; Georgia Railroad; Western Railway of Alabama; Clinchfield Railway Company; Atlanta Joint Terminal Railways; and August, 1955 (Box 517, Folder 3)
      April-September 1955.
    - Louisville and Nashville Railway Company; Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway Company; Atlanta and West Point Railway Company; Georgia Railroad; Western Railway of Alabama; Clinchfield Railway Company; Atlanta Joint Terminal Railways; and August, 1955 (Box 517, Folder 4)
    - Louisville and Nashville Railway Company; Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway Company; Atlanta and West Point Railway Company; Georgia Railroad; Western Railway of Alabama; Clinchfield Railway Company; Atlanta Joint Terminal Railways; and August, 1955 (Box 517, Folder 5)
      April 13, 1955-May 2, 1955.
    - Louisville and Nashville Railway Company; Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway Company; Atlanta and West Point Railway Company; Georgia Railroad; Western Railway of Alabama; Clinchfield Railway Company; Atlanta Joint Terminal Railways; and August, 1955 (Box 517, Folder 6)
      June 4-15, 1955.
    - Louisville and Nashville Railway Company; Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway Company; Atlanta and West Point Railway Company; Georgia Railroad; Western Railway of Alabama; Clinchfield Railway Company; Atlanta Joint Terminal Railways; and August, 1955-1958 (Box 517, Folder 7)
      June 1955-58.
    - Louisville and Nashville Railway Company; Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway Company; Atlanta and West Point Railway Company; Georgia Railroad; Western Railway of Alabama; Clinchfield Railway Company; Atlanta Joint Terminal Railways; and August, 1955-1957 (Box 517, Folder 8)
    - Louisville and Nashville Railway Company; Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway Company; Atlanta and West Point Railway Company; Georgia Railroad; Western Railway of Alabama; Clinchfield Railway Company; Atlanta Joint Terminal Railways; and August, 1955 (Box 517, Folder 9)
    - Railway Express Agency, Inc.; Detroit, Michigan; Milwaukee, Wisconsin; Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1954-1955 (Box 517, Folder 10)
      May 1954-55.
    - Railway Express Agency, Inc.; Detroit, Michigan; Milwaukee, Wisconsin; Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1953-1954 (Box 517, Folder 11)
      December 1953-April 1954.
    - Railway Express Agency, Inc.; Detroit, Michigan; Milwaukee, Wisconsin; Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1953 (Box 518, Folder 1)
      October 28, 1953-November 1953.
    - Railway Express Agency, Inc.; Detroit, Michigan; Milwaukee, Wisconsin; Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1953 (Box 518, Folder 2)
      September 1953-October 27, 1953.
    - General, 1953-1954 (Box 518, Folder 3)
      October 1953-August 1954.
    - General, 1952-1953 (Box 518, Folder 4)
      July 1952-September 1953.
    - General, 1952 (Box 518, Folder 5)
      January-June 1952.
    - General, 1950-1951 (Box 518, Folder 6)
      November 1950-51.
    - General, 1950 (Box 518, Folder 7)
      August 3, 1950-October 1950.
    - General, 1949-1950 (Box 518, Folder 8)
      October 1949-August 2, 1950.
    - General, 1948-1949 (Box 518, Folder 9)
      December 1948-September 1949.
    - General, 1947-1948 (Box 518, Folder 10)
      1947-November 1948.
    - General, 1946 (Box 518, Folder 11)
    - General, 1941-1945 (Box 518, Folder 12)
    - General, 1934-1940 (Box 518, Folder 13)
    - General. Cassidy, A. and Grimshaw, F. Placed on Unfair List by LaSalle Trades and Labor Council, 1939-1946 (Box 518, Folder 14)
    - General. International Brotherhood of Teamsters Boycott of Railway Express Agency, Kansas City, Missouri, 1941-1943 (Box 518, Folder 15)
    - General. Clippings, 1939-1940 (Box 519, Folder 1)
      September 27, 1939-September 11, 1940.
    - General, 1924 (Box 519, Folder 2)
    - General, 1929 (Box 519, Folder 3)
    - General, 1927 (Box 519, Folder 4)
    - General, 1925 (Box 519, Folder 5)
    - General, 1924-1925 (Box 519, Folder 6)
  - Sub-Series 342-6. Strikes
    - Norfolk and Western Railroad, 1928-1939 (Box 519, Folder 7)
    - Norfolk and Western Railroad, 1920 (Box 519, Folder 8)
  - Sub-Series 342-8. Strikes
    - Unauthorized Strike at Railway Express Agency, New York, New York, 1933 (Box 519, Folder 9)
    - Unauthorized Strike at Railway Express Agency, New York, New York. Clippings, 1928 (Box 519, Folder 10)
  - Sub-Series 342-9. Strikes
    - Toledo, Peoria, and Western Railroad, 1929-1952 (Box 519, Folder 11)
  - Sub-Series 342-10. Strikes
    - Illinois Central Railroad, 1931 (Box 519, Folder 12)
  - Sub-Series 342-11. Strikes
    - Michigan Central, 1932 (Box 519, Folder 13)
  - Sub-Series 342-12. Strikes
    - Illegal Strike at Universal Carloading and Distributing Company, Cleveland, Ohio, 1933 (Box 519, Folder 14)
    - Michigan Central Railway. NMB Case No. A-5935, 1961 (Box 519, Folder 15)
  - Sub-Series 342-13. Strikes
    - Central of Georgia Railroad, 1961 (Box 519, Folder 16)
    - Central of Georgia Railroad, 1960 (Box 519, Folder 17)
  - Sub-Series 342-14. Strikes
    - United Textile Workers of America, 1934 (Box 519, Folder 18)
  - Sub-Series 342-15. Strikes
    - Santa Fe Railway, 1962 (Box 519, Folder 19)
    - International Brotherhood of Teamsters at A&P Company, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1934 (Box 519, Folder 20)
  - Sub-Series 342-16. Strikes
    - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Decatur, Illinois, 1935 (Box 519, Folder 21)
  - Sub-Series 342-17. Strikes
    - Railroad Express Agency. NMB Case No. A-6998, 1963-1964 (Box 519, Folder 22)
    - Railroad Express Agency. NMB Case No. A-6998, 1960-1962 (Box 519, Folder 23)
    - International Brotherhood of Teamsters at Mier and Frank Department Store, Portland, Oregon, 1935 (Box 519, Folder 24)
  - Sub-Series 342-18. Strikes
    - Southern Pacific Railway Company. NMB Case No. A-7082, 1962-1964 (Box 519, Folder 25)
    - Southern Pacific Railway Company. NMB Case No. A-7082, 1964 (Box 519, Folder 26)
    - Southern Pacific Railway Company. NMB Case No. A-7082. June 1, 1963 Wage Demand, 1964 (Box 519, Folder 27)
    - Southern Pacific Railway Company. NMB Case No. A-6617, 1963-1964 (Box 519, Folder 28)
      February 28, 1963-64.
    - Southern Pacific Railway Company. NMB Case No. A-6617, 1961-1963 (Box 519, Folder 29)
      1961-February 27, 1963.
    - Order of Railroad Telegraphers at Southern Pacific Railway, 1961 (Box 519, Folder 30)
    - International Brotherhood of Teamsters at William H. Block Company, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1936 (Box 519, Folder 31)
  - Sub-Series 342-19. Strikes
    - United Leather Workers International Union at Vici Kid Company, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1936 (Box 519, Folder 32)
  - Sub-Series 342-20. Strikes
    - Pennsylvania Railroad, 1962 (Box 519, Folder 33)
    - Pennsylvania Railroad, 1960 (Box 519, Folder 34)
    - United Rubber Workers of America at Goodyear Rubber Company, Akron, Ohio, 1936 (Box 519, Folder 35)
    - International Transport Workers Union at Pennsylvania Railroad, 1960 (Box 519, Folder 36)
  - Sub-Series 342-21. Strikes
    - Great Northern Railway. Ore Dock Notice, 1962 (Box 519, Folder 37)
      1962 March, 1
    - International Brotherhood of Teamsters at Blumauer Frank Drug Company, 1936-1937 (Box 519, Folder 38)
  - Sub-Series 342-22. Strikes
    - Northern Pacific Railway. Ore Dock Notice, 1962 (Box 519, Folder 39)
    - International Association of Machinists at Remington Rand Company, 1936-1937 (Box 519, Folder 40)
  - Sub-Series 342-23. Strikes
    - International Brotherhood of Teamsters at Reading Transportation Company, 1937 (Box 519, Folder 41)
  - Sub-Series 342-24. Strikes
    - Soo Line Railroad. Ore Dock Notice, 1962 (Box 519, Folder 42)
    - Soo Line Railroad. Soo Line Central Agency Plan. Wisconsin Docket 2-R-4422, 1963 (Box 519, Folder 43)
    - Chicago, Milwaukee, St. Paul, and Pacific Railroad Company, 1960 (Box 519, Folder 44)
    - Unauthorized Strike at Erie Freight Handlers (Seaboard Terminal), 1937 (Box 519, Folder 45)
  - Sub-Series 342-25. Strikes
    - Missouri-Kansas-Texas Railway. NMB Case No. 6280, 1961 (Box 519, Folder 46)
    - Kingham Trailer Company. Louisville, Kentucky, 1937 (Box 519, Folder 47)
  - Sub-Series 342-26. Strikes
    - Engineers', Firemen's, and Switchmen's Unions, 1948 (Box 519, Folder 48)
  - Sub-Series 342-27. Strikes
    - Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen and Order of Railway Conductors, 1950-1952 (Box 519, Folder 49)
  - Sub-Series 342-28. Strikes
    - Chesapeake and Ohio Railway, 1963 (Box 519, Folder 50)
  - Sub-Series 342-29. Strikes
    - Western Pacific Railway. NMB Case No. A-5869, 1961 (Box 519, Folder 51)
    - Denver Union Terminal Railway, 1956-1959 (Box 519, Folder 52)
  - Sub-Series 342-30. Strikes
    - Masters, Mates, and Pilots and Marine Engineers' Beneficial Association at American Coal Shipping, Inc., 1956-1959 (Box 520, Folder 1)
  - Sub-Series 342-31. Strikes
    - International Brotherhood of Teamsters at Railway Express Agency; Detroit, Michigan; Milwaukee, Wisconsin; Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania; Cleveland, Ohio; Cincinnati, Ohio; Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1957-1958 (Box 520, Folder 2)
    - International Brotherhood of Teamsters at Railway Express Agency; Detroit, Michigan; Milwaukee, Wisconsin; Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania; Cleveland, Ohio; Cincinnati, Ohio; Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Appeal of Lodge No. 2176 for Strike Benefits, 1957-1959 (Box 520, Folder 3)
    - International Brotherhood of Teamsters at Railway Express Agency; Detroit, Michigan; Milwaukee, Wisconsin; Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania; Cleveland, Ohio; Cincinnati, Ohio; Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Appeal of Lodge No. 2219 for Strike Benefits, 1957-1959 (Box 520, Folder 4)
  - Sub-Series 342-32. Strikes
    - Santa Fe Railroad, 1957-1958 (Box 520, Folder 5)
      November 13, 1957-58.
    - Santa Fe Railroad, 1957 (Box 520, Folder 6)
      September 1957-November 12, 1957.
  - Sub-Series 342-35. Strikes
    - St. Louis-San Francisco Railroad. NMB Case No. A-6764, 1962-1963 (Box 520, Folder 7)
      1962-October 1963.
  - Sub-Series 342-38. Strikes
    - New York Central Railroad. NMB Case No. A-5935, 1961-1962 (Box 520, Folder 8)
      1961-April 1962.
    - New York Central Railroad. Possible Strike by Transport Workers Union, 1962 (Box 520, Folder 9)
      1962 January
    - New York Central Railroad. Possible Strike by Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen, 1961 (Box 520, Folder 10)
      1961 January
  - Sub-Series 342-41. Strikes
    - Boston and Albany Railway. NMB Case No. A-5935, 1961 (Box 520, Folder 11)
  - Sub-Series 342-54. Strikes
    - Chicago, Milwaukee, St. Paul, and Pacific Railroad, 1960 (Box 520, Folder 12)
  - Sub-Series 342-57. Strikes
    - Chicago and Northwestern Railroad. Ore Dock Notice, 1962 (Box 520, Folder 13)
    - Chicago and Northwestern Railroad. NMB Case No. 6443, 1960-1964 (Box 520, Folder 14)
  - Sub-Series 342-65. Strikes
    - Belt Railway Company of Chicago. NMB Cases Nos. A-6954, A-6955 (Box 520, Folder 15)
  - Sub-Series 342-66. Strikes
    - Pittsburgh and Lake Erie Railway. NMB Case No. A-5935, 1961 (Box 520, Folder 16)
  - Sub-Series 342-84. Strikes
    - Missouri Pacific Railway. NMB Case No. 3245, 1962 (Box 520, Folder 17)
    - Missouri Pacific Railway. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Local No. 600, 1960 (Box 520, Folder 18)
  - Sub-Series 342-96. Strikes
    - Rutland Railway, 1960-1961 (Box 520, Folder 19)
  - Sub-Series 342-108. Strikes
    - Chicago and Western Indiana Railroad. NMB Cases Nos. A-6954, A-6955, 1963 (Box 520, Folder 20)
  - Sub-Series 342-112. Strikes
    - Cleveland, Cincinnati, Chicago, and St. Louis Railway. NMB Case No. A-5935, 1961 (Box 520, Folder 21)
  - Sub-Series 342-117. Strikes
    - Terminal Railroad Association of St. Louis. NMB Case No. A-6519, 1961 (Box 520, Folder 22)
  - Sub-Series 342-120. Strikes
    - Missouri Pacific Railway, Gulf District. NMB Case No. 3245, 1962 (Box 520, Folder 23)
  - Sub-Series 342-123. Strikes
    - Grand Trunk Western Railroad, 1960 (Box 520, Folder 24)
  - Sub-Series 342-124. Strikes
    - Indiana Harbor Belt Railway Company. NMB Case No. A-5935, 1961 (Box 520, Folder 25)
  - Sub-Series 342-127. Strikes
    - Denver and Rio Grande Western Railway. NMB Case No. A-6497, 1961 (Box 520, Folder 26)
    - Denver and Rio Grande Western Railway. NMB Case No. A-6497, 1960 (Box 520, Folder 27)
  - Sub-Series 342-134. Strikes
    - Chicago Junction, Chicago River, and Indiana Railway Company. NMB Case No. A-5935, 1961 (Box 520, Folder 28)
  - Sub-Series 342-154. Strikes
    - Duluth, Missabe, and Iron Range Railroad, 1961 (Box 520, Folder 29)
    - Duluth, Missabe, and Iron Range Railroad. Ore Dock Notice, 1962 (Box 520, Folder 30)
  - Sub-Series 342-180. Strikes
    - Columbus and Greenville Railroad, 1961 (Box 520, Folder 31)
  - Sub-Series 342-181. Strikes
    - Lake Superior and Ishpeming Railroad. Ore Dock Notice, 1962 (Box 520, Folder 32)
    - Lake Superior and Ishpeming Railroad, 1961 (Box 520, Folder 33)
  - Sub-Series 342-188. Strikes
    - Chicago Union Station. Notice of August 10, 1964 (Box 520, Folder 34)
  - Sub-Series 342-209. Strikes
    - Monongahela Railway Company. NMB Case No. A-5935, 1961 (Box 520, Folder 35)
  - Sub-Series 342-227. Strikes
    - Universal Carloading Company. Notice of February 28, 1963, 1962 (Box 520, Folder 36)
    - Universal Carloading Company. 1961 National Wage Movement (Box 520, Folder 37)
  - Sub-Series 342-246. Strikes
    - Acme Fast Freight, Inc., 1960 (Box 520, Folder 38)
  - Sub-Series 342-375. Strikes
    - New York Central Building Corporation. NMB Case No. A-5935, 1961 (Box 520, Folder 39)
  - Sub-Series 342-380. Strikes
    - Santa Fe Trail Transportation Company, 1961 (Box 520, Folder 40)
  - Sub-Series 342-390. Strikes
    - Philadelphia, Bethlehem, and New England Railway Company. NMB Case No. A-6813, 1962 (Box 520, Folder 41)
  - Sub-Series 342-416. Strikes
    - Flight Engineers' International Association at Pan American World Airways, Inc., 1961-1962 (Box 520, Folder 42)
      1961-March 18, 1962.
    - Flight Engineers' International Association at Pan American World Airways, Inc., 1960 (Box 520, Folder 43)
  - Sub-Series 342-437. Strikes
    - International Association of Machinists at Northwest Airlines, 1960-1961 (Box 520, Folder 44)
  - Sub-Series 342-488. Strikes
    - Western Airlines, 1961 (Box 520, Folder 45)
    - Western Airlines, 1955-1959 (Box 520, Folder 46)
  - Sub-Series 342-517. Strikes
    - Braniff Airways, Inc., 1960-1961 (Box 520, Folder 47)
      October 5, 1960-March 1961.
    - Braniff Airways, Inc. Thomas, E.R., Lodge No. 3053, 1960-1961 (Box 521, Folder 1)
    - Braniff Airways, Inc., 1960 (Box 521, Folder 2)
      August 1960-October 4, 1960.
  - Sub-Series 342-675. Strikes
    - New Orleans Union Passenger Terminal, 1961 (Box 521, Folder 3)
  - Sub-Series 342-730. Strikes
    - Republic Carloading Company, 1961 (Box 521, Folder 4)